Guide to the Alison Jolly papers, circa 1919-2014
Jolly, Alison papers
- Series III. Notes and Papers
  - General Documents
    - An Apparent Lunar Periodicity in the Sexual Cycle of Certain Prosimians Author: Ursula Cowgill, R.J. Cowgill, G.E. Hutchinson, Alison Bishop Location: Yales, 1962; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Control of the Hand in Lower Primates Author: Alison Jolly Location: Yale, 1962; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Use of the Hand in Lower Primates Author: Alison Bishop Location: Yale, 1962; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Choice of Cue in Prosimian Learning Author: Alison Jolly Location: Yale, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Prosimians Manipulation of Simple Object Problems Author: Alison Jolly Location: Yale, 1964; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Lemur Social Behaviour and Primate Intelligence Author: Alison Bishop Location: Berenty, 1966; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Malagasy lemurs - clues to our past Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1967; article (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - A Handbook of Living Primates Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1968; book review (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Observations on Galago crassicaudatus sent to B.G.F. Sauer Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lusaka, Zambia, 1966; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cycles Genitaux Saisonnieres de Mammiferes Sauvages (R. Canivenc, ed.) Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1968; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Soul of the Ape Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1969; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Stability of Territorial Boundaries in a Lemur Troop Author: Alison Jolly and P.H. Klopper Berenty, 1970; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Troop Continuity and troop spacing in Propithecus verreauxi and lemur catta at Berenty Author: AJ Berenty, 1972; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hour of Birth in Primates and Man Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1972; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Primate Birth Hour Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1973; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Study of Primate Infancy Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1974; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Population, espace vital et composition des groupes chez le maki et le sifaka Author: AJ, Gustafson, Mertl, Ramanantsoa Berenty, 1975; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Lemur behaviour and Populations Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1978; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Conservation in Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1978; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Frustrating search for the monkey with a lion's tail Author: Alison Jolly Location: India, western Ghats, 1979; article (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Comparative Ecology and Behaviour of Primates Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1971; book review (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Study of Prosimian Behaviour Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1979; book review (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Beyond the Green Revolution Author: Alison Jolly and RJ Location: Lewes, 1979; book review (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Tenrecs Author: AJ Lewes, 1970s?; Book Review (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Chimpanzees' Tea Party, BBS Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1978; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Can't we have it both ways? Commentary on Parker and Gibson. BBS Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1979; book review (typed draft) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Aspects of the behaviour of the Sifaka Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1973; letter and review (typed) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Man, the Promising Primate, Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1973; letter and review (typed) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - The Aye-Aye of Madagascar (film) Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1972-3; letter and typed draft (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Primate Studies Author: AJ Lewes, 1974; review (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Propithecus Verreauxi Population and Ranging at Berenty Author: AJ, H. Gustafson, W.L.R. Oliver, S.M. O'connor Berenty, 1982; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Population and Troop Ranges of Lemur Catta and Lemur fulvus at Berenty Author: AJ, W.L.R. Oliver, S.M. O'Connor Berenty, 1982; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Island of the dodo is down to its last few native species Author: Alison Jolly Location: Mauritious, 1982; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - lemurs Author: AJ Madagascar, 1984; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Puzzle of Female Feeding Priority Author: Alison Jolly Location: Rockefeller, 1984; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Evolution of Primate Behaviour Author: Alison Jolly Location: Rockefeller, 1985; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Predatory Behaviour in captive lemur spp Author: Alison Jolly and W.L.R. Oliver Location: Durrell, Jersey, 1985; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - A new science that sees animals as conscious beings Author: Alison Jolly Location: Rockefeller, 1985; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Science fiction Author: AJ Princeton, 1986; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Lemur Survival Author: AJ Madagascar, 1986; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Meeting the Bizarre and Marvellous Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1987; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Madagascar: A World Apart Author: Alison Jolly Madagascar, 1987; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Evolution of Purpose Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1988; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mad. Lemurs: On the edge of survival Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1988; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The World's wild places Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1988; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Madagascar Challenge: human needs and fragile eco systems Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1989; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Greenhouse Effect and Biological Diversity Author: Alison Jolly and D. Rubenstein Princeton, 1989; article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Natural History of the Gorilla Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1981; book review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dennett's "Panglossian paradigm" Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1983; book review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Manwatching Author: AJ Princeton, 1980?; book review (typed draft) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Malayan Primates, David Chivers (ed.) Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1980?; book review (typed draft) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Nocturnal Malagay Primates Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1980?; book review (typed draft) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Panglossian Paradigm Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1983; commentary, typed (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Boiling down intelligence Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1980s; commentary, typed (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Harsh times for Madagascar's growing numbers Author: Alison Jolly Location: Madagascar, 1988; newspaper article (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Talking of Primates Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1981; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Woman who never evolved Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1982; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Reproductive Biology of the Great Apes: Comparative and Biomedical Perspectives Author: AJ Princeton, 1982; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - A Life among the Chimpanzees Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1986; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Fildes, Breasts, Bottles and Babies: A History of Infant feeding Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1986; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Human Birth: An Evolutionary Perspective Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1987; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Woman of the Mists Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1988; review (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - How Monkeys see the World Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Social Intelligence and Sexual Reproduction: Evolutionary Gambles Author: Alison Jolly Location: Santa Cruz, 1990; Manuscript typed (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Jantschke card Author: Fritz Jantschke Berenty, 1991; handwritten card (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Primate Visions Author: Aj, MJ Princeton, 1991; reviews (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Female Biology and Women Biologists Author: Alison Jolly Location: Santa Cruz, 1991; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The Rise and Fall of the Third Chimpanzee Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Walking with the Great Apes Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Conscious Chimpanzees? A review of recent literature Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1991; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Harsh Lessons in the art of suvival Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1992; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - What really happened in Rio? Author: Alison Jolly Rio de Janeiro, 1993; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Missing Links, Visions of Caliban: On Chimpanzees and people Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1993; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Reinventing the future: conversations with the world's leading scientists Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1993; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Territoriality in Lemur Catta groups during the birth season Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1993; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - How to see lemurs Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1995; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Whistling Apes and Talking Drums Author: Alison Jolly Location: Zaire, 1995; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Presidents Corner Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1995; newsletter (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - International Primatological Society Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1996; letters (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Maternal Responses to Dead and Dying Infants in Wild Troops of Ring-tailed Lemurs Author: AJ Berenty, 1996; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Why is sex fun? The evolution of human sexuality Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1997; review and letter (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bonobo, The Forgotton Ape Author: Alison Jolly Princeton, 1997; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Pair-bonding, Female Aggression and the Evolution of Lemur Societies Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1998; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Machiavellian Intelligence 11. Extensions and evaluations Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1998; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Remaking Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly, 1998; review (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - A Brief History of Conservation in Madagascar Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1998; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Troop histories and range inertia of Lemur catta at Berenty, Madagascar: a 33 year perspective Author: AJ Princeton, 1999; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Alison Jolly Author: Caroline Moseley Location: Princeton, 1990s?; article (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - IPS Newsletter, Presidents corner Location: Princeton, 1990s - 2001; newsletters (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Pitching it right: Observing chimps and the women who observe chimps Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 2000; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Fifth Step Author: AJ Lewes, 2000; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Battlefield Sociobiology Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2000; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Infant Killing, Wounding and Predation in Eulemur and Lemur Author: AJ, S.Caless, S. Cavigelli, L. Gould, M.Epereira, A. Pitts, R.E. Pride, H.D. Rabenandrasana, J.D. Walker, T. Zafison Berenty, 2000; article, paper (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Keep Me Author: AJ Lewes, 2000; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Monkeys in the Back Garden Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2001; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Love at Goon Park: Harry Harlow and the Science of Affection Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 2002; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Diary Author: AJ Berenty, 2003; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Sick as a Parrot Author: Alison Jolly and V. Curtis Lewes, 2003; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Flat Feet, Clever Hands Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2004; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Love, Actually Author: AJ Lewes, 2004; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Wide Spectrum of Sex and Gender Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 2004; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Last Great Apes? Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2005; article (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Life and Death in Sumatra Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2005; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - A Global Vision Author: AJ Lewes, 2006; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Social Origin of Mind Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2007; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Macachavellian Intelligence Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2007; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Primate Passions Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 2007; review (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Narrator's Stance: Storytelling and Science at Berenty Reserve Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2011; Typed article (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Berenty tourism typed letter and calendar (2006) Author: RJ, Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, typed letter (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Eulemur fulvus census Author: Susan Pinkus Location: Berenty, 1993; papers, photos and notes (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Influences des conditions de l'habitat sur les structures de la papulation de propithecus verreauxi verreauxi Author: Soava Victor Rakotoarisoa Location: Berenty, paper, notes and tables (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Wrist flexion as a distinction between lemuroid and lorisoid prehensive grasps Author: AJ, Zackary Taylor Berenty, 1999; paper, notes and discs (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - prints, photos and stamps Location: Haiti, 1970s-80s; photos, stamps (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Lemur behaviour Author: AMKB, Hugh Rowell, RJ Location: Berenty, 1965; drawings and photos (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Alison Jolly Thesis Author: AJ, AMKB Yale, 1963; original plates and negs (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Alison Jolly Thesis Author: AJ, AMKB Yale, 1963; original plates and negs (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Flight from Morondava Author: Alison Jolly Kirindy, Analabe, Tsingy, Bongolava, 1975; photos, stamps (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Lucys Legacy illustrations Author: Stephen Nash, 1950s-90s; letters, photos and cartoons (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Photos and prints, 1960s onwards (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Jean de Heaulme portrait, photos (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Jean de Heaulme originals, photos (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - RJ and Alison Jolly photos Author: RJ, Alison Jolly Anzamahavelo, 2000; photos (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Adrian Warren "Sapphire" Author: Adrian Warren Location: Berenty, 1996; photo (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Calao Postcards Author: de Heaulme Fort Dauphin, 1990s; postcards (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Photos from Yale Author: John BJ, Alison Jolly Yale, 1960s; photos (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Madagascar stamps Location: Madagascar, envelopes with stamps (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Noel Rowe, Earthwatch Author: Noel Rowe Location: Berenty, 1984; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Alison Jolly photos Location: Berenty, 1964; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - L. catta photo named Alison Jolly Location: Portland, Oregon, 1985; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Alison Jolly in Arashiyama IPS congress, 1992; photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - funny pictures of slender loris for Alison Jolly thesis Author: Subramoniam, S. Location:, 1957; illustrations (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Jean de Heaulm and tortoise Author: Russ Mittermeier Location: Berenty, 1970s; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Precision Grip Author: John Napier, 1960; photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Lemur Mongoz Comoros Author: Alan Walker, 1970s; photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Hanta and friends Location: Berenty, 1984; handwritten letter and photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - original photo of Tupaia, 1960; magazine photo (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - drawings of G. crassi-caudatus, Varecia and Aye-aye hand Author: Rogers Location:, 1965; lettter and drawings (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Nash paintings of Megaladapis, Paleopropithecus, Archeolemur Author: Stephen Nash Location:, 1987; prints (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Sue Savage-Rumbaugh with Kanzi Bonobo and infant chimps, 1988; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Tupaia Hapalemur photos Author: Alison Jolly Yale, 1962; photos (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - classic primate photos, 1959-60; letter, envelope and photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - captive pottos Author: AJ Yale, 1962; photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - lepilemur photos Location: Yale and Berenty, 1960-70; photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Galago crassicaudatus in caged trees Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lusaka, 1965; photo and negs (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Loris Author: Marcel Hladik Sri Lanka, 1962; photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Avahi sonnerat, Aye aye, prints (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - girls with pet ringtailed lemur, photo (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Filanzana watercolour, 1989; watercolour prints (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - A murder in Madagascar Author: David Quammen Location: Madagascar, 1991; magazine article with photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Leapin' lemurs, 1983; magazine article with photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Catalogue of lemur skins in the IRSM Author: AJ, Georges Randrianasolo Location: Antananarivo, 1963; handwritten notes (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Murder at the Wenner Gren Castle Author: Alison Jolly Location: Burg Wartenstein, Austria, 1969; Typed detective story (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Burnt Barley Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1969; Typed stories (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Primate species distribution and biogeographic provinces Author: Alison Jolly Location: Lewes, 1970s; Typed paper draft and maps (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - A note on infant adoption by a male Lemur Catta Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 1975; Typed paper draft (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - The Rediscovery of Death Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1970s; Typed paper draft (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Letter to Gillian Beer. Biologist's reaction to "Darwin's Plots" Author: Alison Jolly Location: From Rome, 1984; Handwritten letter (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Nationl Geographic conservation proposal Author: Alison Jolly Location: New York, 1985; Typed draft, letters (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Le Chant de Lemur catta: son rôle dans la défense de territoire et l'éducation des americains.. Author: Alison Jolly Antananarivo, 1985; Typed seminar draft (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Reality Check Author: Caroline Moseley Location: Princeton, 1986; Newspaper (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Structural adjustment and child malnutrition in Mad., Impact of World Recession on the Third World: The Case of Zambia Author: RJ, Catholic Relief Services Location: Antananarivo, Zambia, 1986; Typed letter, paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - The Environment is where we all live Author: Alison Jolly Location: Delhi, 1987; Typed paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - National Geographic, Lemur proposal Author: Alison Jolly Location: New York, 1987; Letters, Budget (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Children, the environment and UNICEF Author: RJ, Alison Jolly Location: New York, 1988; Typed paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Haraway, Donna: Teddy Bear Postmodernism Lecture Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1990s; Typed notes (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Intelligence: the best idea since sex Author: Alison Jolly Location: Santa Cruz, 1990s; Workshop paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - A note on female dominance and social structure in the lemurifornes Author: Alison Jolly Location: Bali, 1994; Conference paper (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Once there was a millionaire who was interested in anthropology Author: Alison Jolly Location: Teresopolis, Brazil, 1996; Typed notes (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Andrew Ate an Ant Author: Alison Jolly Lewes, 1976; Hand drawn children's book (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Ann adopted an Adder sample illustrations, Andrew ate an ant Author: AJ, Victoria Cowan Lewes, 1979; incomplete book, pen and ink on card (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Rejection letters Author: various London, 1978-9; Typed letters (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Murder on the Bird Tour Author: Alison Jolly Mauritius, 1980; Typed detective story (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Bonobo Field notebook Author: Alison Jolly Wamba, Zaire, 1994; small notebook (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Bonobo Anthropologist Author: Alison Jolly Wamba, Zaire, 1994; address (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Talking drum letter Author: Lingomo-Bongoli Location: Wamba, Zaire, 1994; handwritten letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Talking drums, squeaking chimpanzees and quarks of speech Author: Alison Jolly Location: Wamba, Zaire, 1994; Typed draft (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Talking drum letter, Lysa Author: Lysa- Location: Princeton, 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Talking drum letter, Steven Pinker Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Talking drum letter Sue Savage-Rumbaugh Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Yoruba talking drums article Author: Ajayi, Bade Location: Nigeria, 1994; Article (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Talking drums letter Author: Sue Savage Rumbaugh Location: Georgia State Univ., 1994; Typed letter (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Protecting bonobos by inalimental conditions: the case of the Bongando Author: Lingomo-Bongoli Wamba, Zaire, 1994; Typed draft (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - The Kiloopy-Loopy-Soofy and the Very Old Man Author: Alison Jolly Location: Princeton, 1995; Typed story (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Behaviour in the Bottleneck Author: Ajayi, Bade Location: Madison, Wisconsin, 1996; Typed draft (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Mark's Maky Author: AJ, 2009; Typed story (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Detective story Author: AJ Madagascar, 1980; Typed story (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Historic Maps of Madagascar Location: Madagascar, maps (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Historic Maps of Madagascar Location: Madagascar, maps (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
    - Document pour le seminaire Location: Madagascar, 2006; document and newspaper (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Report of CARE's 2003 joint baseline surveys Author: Megan Deitchler and Gilles Bergeron Antanarivo and Fort Dauphin, Madagascar, 2004; document (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Madagascar food insecurity Location: Madagascar, 2003; map (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Madagascar aids law Location: Madagascar, 2005; document (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - USAID SAVEM meetings Location: Madagascar, 1997; notes and document (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - USAID PE2 meetings Location: Madagascar, 1997; document (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - small notebook Author: AJ Madagascar, 2002; handwritten notes (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Des racines pour des ailes Author: Roland Ramahatra Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - projet radio Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Victor Ramahatra Author: Nivo Ramahatra Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed letter (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Conservation of critical biodiversity habitats 1990 to present Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Sustainable use of forest resources 1990 to present Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Involvement of private sector in better managing natural resources Location: Madagascar, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Twelve years later Location: Madagascar and Washington, 2002; typed report (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - revue strategique du programme de l'usaid Location: Madagascar, 2001; document (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - letters from Harvard Press and Houghton Mifflin on Lords and Lemurs Location: Princeton and Berenty, 2001-2; typed letters (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Lords and Lemurs statements Location: Berenty, 2000; typed notes (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - official documents Berenty estate Location: Berenty, 1930s-50s; documents (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - original notebooks Author: Alison Jolly Berenty, 1998-2000; handritten notebooks (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - notes and interviews for Lords and Lemurs Author: Alison Jolly Location:, 2000s?; notes, notebooks, typed and handwritten (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Narrator's Stance: storytelling and Science at Berenty Reserve Author: Alison Jolly Location: Berenty, 2010; Typed article (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Permissions, 2000s; typed letters (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Robert Drury Location: Princeton, 2003; manuscripts and letters (Box 4, Folder 13)